



UBS

Pune, India
+91 9677045190
hemachandar.pamanji@gmail.com

HEMACHANDAR PAMANJI

DEVOPS ENGINEER

OBJECTIVE

A forward thinking, capable and committed DevOps engineer with a proven ability to meet agreed deadlines, co-ordinate work within a structured environment. Focused on any task at hand and able to utilize existing knowledge and experiences to come up with practical solutions and alternatives to improvise the processes. Having first class executive leadership, negotiating, communicating skills, capable of providing authoritative guidance and advice to both in house and third party teams.

RELEASE ENGINEER CAPABILITIES

Capability Items

Evaluating the teams on process framework implementation and gathering common challenges

Extensively worked to bring the best industry practices like **GEMBA & KAIZEN approaches** across the teams Coaching the teams on release process best practices

TECHNICAL CAPABILITIES

Capability Items	Level Of Skill Set
Branching Strategies & Code review process (SVN, Git hub)	Expertise
Experience in Python and Pearl scripting languages	Expertise
Good working knowledge on CI & CD tools (Jenkins, Team City)	Expertise
Branching Strategies & Code review process (SVN, Git hub)	Expertise
Experience in writing Unix shell scripts	Expertise
Experience in creating and maintaining Autosys Jobs and crontab	Expertise
Implementing Web services using REST, JSON	Expertise
Design and Develop Web User Interface using HTML5, CSS, JSP, Jquery	Expertise
Continuous integration with Jenkins	Expertise
Spring Core for dependency injection/Inversion of control (IOC)	Expertise
Designing Automation framework architectures	Expertise
Developing Automation projects from scratch to stable state	Expertise
Bringing down different Automation projects into single architecture	Expertise
Designing internal tool for various Test Automation /manual infrastructures	Expertise
Preparation of Automation Test environments & test beds	Expertise
QTP (UFT), Selenium(webdriver2 & 3) , Test Complete	Expertise
Silk test, Coded UI & Open script	Good

Capability Items	Level Of Skill Set
Manual testing concepts	Expertise
SDLC, STLC, Bug life cycle, testing strategies like testing methodologies, levels of testing, testing	
approaches, types of testing and testing models	Expertise
Data Modeling & integration testing via ETL testing tools (SSIS) & its life cycle	Good
Defect tracking tools like Bugzilla, QC, Jira and TFS	Expertise
Working with client server & Web based AUT 's	Expertise
R & D on many open source tools	Good
Good experience in providing Solution Definition	Expertise

OTHER CAPABILITIES

RELEASE ENGINEER GOVERANCES & AUDITING

Items

Involved internal & external audits

As a Release Manager remodeled build and release governances & practices

Involved in many Release process reengineering activates

CAREER HIGHLIGHTS

Highlights

8 years of experience in the IT Industry with effective communication, analytical & problem resolution skills coupled with exceptional work ethics and integrity.

Worked in different geographical locations like India, USA

Designated in different kind of roles as QA Engineer to Analyst Programmer & In Agile world as Scrum Master & Agile Developer etc.

Expertise in working with offshore- onshore models

Good experience in **Financial Product based industries**

Handled financial business critical projects like Credit Trade Capturing, Mortgage Risk Manager, Security Master Strategic Vision – Pricing and Security Master Strategic Vision – Reference Data

Worked for Security Master Reference Data automation at Fidelity Investments - USA & Chennai

Worked for Security Master Pricing automation at Fidelity Investments – Chennai

Successfully executed Deployment Automation projects for USAA at Fidelity Investments – USA

DOMAINS WORKED ON

Domains

Investment Banking

Security Master

Mutual Funds

Credit

Mortgages

WORK EXPERIENCE

CRM | Build & Release Engineer | UBS | India

Aug, 2018 - Till Date

Deploying Risk Manager application. The goal of this project is to provide a responsive web user interface for the mortgage users to view and calculate the Risk Measures for various products like CMO, CMBS, Agency and Non Agency bonds.

- Responsible for builds and ensuring the completion of Deployments on various environments
- Deployment in pre-production as well as production environments and troubleshoot the build errors.
- Deploying, patching and maintaining applications.
- Planning of the Releases as part of Release Management.
- Performing UAT to prod DB Schema comparison using TOAD.
- Verifying Autosys BATCH jobs in QA and UAT environments and ensure their successful run
- Communicating with other interfacing teams like Development, E2E Testing, Downstream applications, etc. for deployment and environment related issues and to deliver the Releases as per deadlines.
- Attending CAB meetings
- Coordinating with various departments during various change implementations.
- Creating Change Tickets and responsible for getting the business approvals
- Build Manager for GitHub repositories
- Worked on team city for release and snapshot builds, trouble shooting and resolving build issues

Credit Trade Capturing | Build & Release Engineer | Bank Of America | India

Nov, 2015 - Aug 2018

Developing Credit Trade Capturing platform in Java. The goal of this project is to provide an efficient platform for middle office to perform trading and post trade actions.

- Maintain and enhance builds, scripts, installation procedures, and systems including source code control and QA/Integration environment
- Maintain CI tools Jenkins and update for new release
- Ensuring daily builds on Development and integration environment
- Managing code on CVS
- Configuration Management using puppet
- Automating deployment process release instructions using puppet modules
- Act as an integrator for continuous build and deployment of the application
- Packaging of the final version using install anywhere and apply the migration of database, providing all the required migration scripts along with the packaged version

SECURITY MASTER - Pricing Core Automation | Test Developer | Fidelity Investments | India

Mar, 2014 – Nov, 2015

Developing Automation scripts for business components in UNIX with **Perl.** The goal of this automation project is to ensure 100 percent test data coverage and reduce testing time. This automation project will ensures the data integrity between the SMSV pricing oracle database and the downstream Mainframe applications

- Updating, Review Test Scenarios and Test Case preparation in QC11 and give inputs to the team
- Prepared **POC and ROI Estimations** for this automation project

- Involved in Test plan revision for the version release
- Performing Automation Testing, Black box and White box testing.
- Ensuring execution of test cases, verifying that all test cases have been executed prior to the release.
- Leading the Team in Creation and Execution of automation tests with HP UFT
- Track all Bug's during the testing process and prior to the release for closure/ resolution
- Coordinate with development and support teams to resolve the issues.
- Responsible for weekly reconciliation testing of the Polar lake Securities pricing application.
- Maintaining automation scripts and Updating the Weekly reports & status updates of testing activities.
- Preparation of Bug analysis report
- Designed internal tools for the Automation process.
- Verification of Automation Scripts developed by the team and provides inputs for optimization.
- Responsible for QA Sign off.

SECURITY MASTER – Reference Data Automation | Test Developer | Fidelity Investments | India

Oct, 2013 – March, 2014

SMSV Reference Data UI will be automated to have effective test execution capability and as a result will save some ROI. The goal of this automation project is to cover the testing of UI functionalities thereby increasing better testing due to shorter and more through testing cycles

- o Performing Automation Testing, Black box and White box testing
- Leading the Team in Creation and Execution of tests in HP UFT
- o Performing Automation Testing Execution and Defect tracking in HP QC
- Coordinate with development and support teams to resolve the issues
- Active participation in triage calls and ensures defect closure
- o Understanding BRD, FRD, Change request documents
- o Developed test cases from test plan and executed regression cycles
- Writing the Integration Test Cases and Executing the Test Cases
- o Preparing the RTM, Delivery Notes, Deviation Notes
- o Maintaining the automation scripts and sharing daily, weekly Status Reports to the Client.
- o Perform Manual Testing Process & Bug Report Generation.
- o Monitoring the working of Securities Pricing and Reference Data applications
- o Responsible for QA Sign off

EDUCATION

• Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering (B.Tech C.S.E)

JNTU Anantapur, (2006-20010) with 62.3 % GPA.

• Intermediate(M.P.C.) from Board of Intermediate Education,

Sri Chaitanya Jr. Kalasala (2000-2002) with 84.0 % GPA.

• S.S.C. from Secondary board

R.C.P School, (1999-2000) with **73.3** % GPA.

CERFICATIONS

• National Stock Exchange NCFM - Financial Markets Certification

	National Stock Exchange NCFM – Security Markets Certification
	Hadoop training from Big Data University
REFERENCES	Will provide on request